Jose Manuel Vergara Florez

Full Stack Developer

Contact

- **Email** jose9909@gmail.com

Summary

As a Full Stack Software Developer with over 7 years of experience, I
have developed mobile and web applications using my proficiency in
React Native, ReactJS, NodeJS, and Java. Through my roles at multiple
companies, I have led multiple projects, contributed to code reviews,
and implemented new technologies to improve application
performance and functionality.

Education

- Graduate

SENA Analyst and developer of Information Systems 2016-2018

Skills

- Technical:
 - Javascript, Typescript

- ReactJS, NextJS
- React Native
- NodeJS, Express

- Languages:
 - Spanish: Native

 English: Full professional proficiency

Experience

- Better Engineer
- Senior Frontend Developer

Feb 2024 - Present

Responsibilities: At Better Engineer, I collaborate with Furnished Finder engineers to refactor their legacy ASP.NET web application using Next.js. My responsibilities include designing and coding the frontend architecture, implementing integrations with Contentful and Amplitude, and establishing coding practices for the team. I also manage a small team of developers during the development of specific features.

Technologies: ReactJS, Next.JS, NodeJS, Tailwind CSS, Contentful, GraphQL.

- Zagalabs
- Senior Full Stack Developer

Apr 2021 – Jan 2024

Responsibilities: At Zagalabs, I served as a Senior Full Stack Developer, playing a key role in the redesign of PuppySpot's consumer site. My responsibilities included improving SEO performance, refactoring legacy code, and creating new pages using ButterCMS. I also conducted code reviews to ensure high-quality code throughout the project.

On the TodayTix project, I built a white-label site for theater ticket sales from scratch using Next.js. This involved integrating all website content with Contentful, creating migration scripts for content model updates, and designing visually customizable components tailored to retailer needs. Additionally, I conducted code reviews and maintained the Node.js repository by adding new endpoints and updating existing ones to align with project requirements.

I was also part of the team responsible for developing and maintaining checkout-related features, such as Ticket Protection and Pay In Local Currency, on both the backend (Groovy) and frontend (Next.js). These features contributed an additional \$3.5M revenue in its first year.

Technologies: ReactJS, Next.JS, NodeJS, Redux, Contentful, Groovy, Java.

- IOV Labs (Taringa!)
- Frontend Developer (Mobile and web)

Sep 2020 - Apr 2021

Responsibilities: As a Front End Developer at IOV Labs, I was responsible for developing new visual components, integrating them with the backend data, and migrating class components to function components on the Taringa! project. Additionally, I conducted code reviews to ensure the highest level of code quality for my peers.

Technologies: React Native, ReactJS, Redux.

- S4N
- Frontend Developer

Jun 2019 - Apr 2021

Responsibilities: As a Front End Developer at S4N, I was part of the development of the main frontend architecture for internal projects, including developing visual components based on provided mockups, integrating frontend views with the backend data, and creating unit and integration tests to achieve a minimum of 85% coverage. Additionally, I conducted proof of concepts for new technologies such as React Native Web and onboarded new team members.

Technologies: ReactJS, React Native, Redux.

- Monitoreo Inteligente
- Software Developer

Aug 2017 – Jun 2019

Responsibilities: As a Software Developer at Monitoreo Inteligente, I led the migration of a legacy Android app to React Native, built new mobile applications from scratch, conducted manual testing, and built and deployed mobile apps to the App Store and Play Store. Additionally, I contributed to the migration of a legacy Flash web application to React. **Technologies:** React Native, ReactJS, MobX.